# **ILLIA DANKO**

# **Software Engineer**



79000 Ukraine

Lviv, UA

🕥 illia-danko



# PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Overall, eleven years of working experience in the field. Have participated in various technologies and programming languages, including Golang, C, C++, Java, Clojure, Javascript, Typescript and Python. Started as a system engineer and was moving to the Web, and Golang, in particular. I'm strongly focused on business' needs, and as a free software user, sometimes consider contributing further back to Open Source.

# **TECH STACK**

General	Purpose	Languages
Concount	1 41 2000	Languages

Golang	g	С	Javascript Ty	pescript CI	ojure	Python	C++ Java		

### Domain Specific Languages, frameworks and databases

Bash	Makefile	CMake	Javascri	pt Postgr	esql	MongoDB	Elasticsearch	ArangoDB	ELisp	Lua
MEX	Html Sa:	ss & Css	React	Protobuf	Grapho	ql				

# **EXPERIENCE**

### Software Engineer

### Aller Media Norway

Nov 2022 - Ongoing

- Ukraine, UA
- Design, develop and maintain core pipeline high throughput services.
- Develop UI Web tools using upstream technologies.
- Implement internal helper tools.
- Troubleshooting high performant components.

#### Stack

Golang design, prototype, implement and maintain services using google pubsub, redis, rest api and graphql, elastic-search, postgresql, docker and kubernetes. Write command line company centric tools.

Typescript / Javascript / React / Next.js implement and maintain UI admin panel using both: client and service side rending.

Bash | ci/cd scripting.

## Software Engineer

### **Aigent**

Dec 2019 - Oct 2022

- Amsterdam, NL
- Design, develop and maintain core pipeline services.
- Implement internal tools.
- Troubleshooting high performant components.
- Refine existing parts.
- Collaborate with clients.

#### Stack

Golang design, prototype, implement and maintain real time low latency microservies using kafka, memcached, rest api, rpcs, protobuf/msgpack, postgresql, arangodb, kubernetes. Write command line tools. Embed C libraries (cgo).

C write ffi libraries for other languages.

Javascript implement ecma5/6 compatible web applications, support react applications. Design, prototype and implement microservices using rest api, protobuf, mqtt, postgresql, kubernetes.

Clojure | implement microservices for features using rest api, elasticsearch, mqtt. Implement internal tools.

Python, Bash | ci/cd scripting.

### Software Engineer

#### **Omnisend**

Feb 2018 - Dec 2019

Lviv, UA

- Design, develop and maintain high performing services.
- Cover with acceptance and e2e tests.

#### Stack

Golang design, implement and support features microsevices using rest api, grpc, nats, nsq, mongodb, kubernetes. Integrate 3d party platforms. Write command line tools.

Javascript Design, prototype and implement microservices using rest api, nsq, nats, mongodb.

Python, Bash ci/cd scripting.

### Test Engineer

#### Here

**i** Jun 2017 - Feb 2018

Lviv, UA

- Design and develop integration testing framework.
- Implement and maintain integration tests for car navigation systems.

#### Stack

Python add features, maintain a testing framework using jenkins, sqlite3, casandra, hadoop map-reduce, aws s3, ec2, route algorithms (djaextra). ci/cd scripting.

Bash ci/cd scripting.

# Middle Software Engineer

#### Cisco

**■** Nov 2015 – Jun 2017

Lviv, UA

- Develop and maintain gateway systems for embedded devices.
- Develop and maintain primitive components and drivers, such as, voip, iptv, vpn.
- Write technical documentation.
- Participate in dmz room setup.
- Maintain and extend dmz testing framework.

#### Stack

C write and maintain modules for embedded equipment, including character and network devices using pki, httpd, tcp, udp, ppp, cgi, soap, tr-69, tr-98, tr-181, ieee 802.11, ethernet, ipv4, ipv6, dhcp.

Python add features to dmz testing framework using git hooks, jenkins, cisco hardware.

## Software Engineer

### **Inside Secure**

**i** Jul 2013 - Nov 2015

- Lviv, UA
- Develop and maintain a stereotyped simulator for credit card vendors.
- Write and maintain integration tests.

### Stack

C++ implement and support visualization desktop gui tools (qt library), maintain nfs smartcards testing framework.

Java add features to mastercard nfs smardcards testing framework, maintain tools.

Python, Bash | ci/cd scripting.

# **LANGUAGES**

English			
Ukrainian			•

# **EDUCATION**

### **Bachelor of Economics**

Volodymyr Dahl East Ukrainian National University

**Sep 2010 - Jun 2013**